LinkedIn

# Dheeraj Kammili

# PROFILE SUMMARY: Field Service Engineer

Technical professional with 3 years of hands-on experience in the field of Semiconductor and Pharmaceutical industries. Highly educated possessing a Bachelors, PG Diploma (level 9) with professional certifications in GMP, construction and semiconductor environment

Seeking an opportunity to enhance my skills and be an asset to the Company

 Passionate for learning and Continuous Improvement; Enthusiastic of leaning new methodologies and technologies. Collaborative, dedicated and adaptable person with excellent presentation and reporting skills

# **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

- Preventive Maintenance (PM), CMMS
- Installation, Calibration, P&ID
- 5S DMAIC, Lean Six Sigma

- PLC/HMI Programming, GMP certified
  - Ethernet, IP addressing, Hydraulics •
- Corrective maintenance, FMEA

- Vision systems, Troubleshooting
- Root Cause Analysis, Networking
- C, Java, Python(basics)

## CAREER EXPERIENCE

# Field Service Engineer, Tokyo Electron Europe Limited, Co. Kildare December 2021 - Present

- Performing the necessary repairs/adjustments by referring to operations and maintenance manuals (both basic & advanced level) to the Semiconductor equipment
- Performing precise temperature testing and calibration for the Semiconductor wafer test equipment
- Performing complete **Installation**, **Commissioning**, **calibration**, **and testing** for semiconductor tools in several international customer sites (in Ireland, France, Germany, UK)
- Ensuring Preventive Maintenance, Corrective maintenance activities are carried out as per the Schedule.
- Constantly updating work orders, PM procedures in accordance with the Field Service Maintenance system
- Experience of reading electrical, Piping diagrams and PLC for troubleshooting of machinery equipment
- Dealing with solenoid valves, cylinders, motors, pumps, and other pneumatic, hydraulic components
- Inspecting, Monitoring, collecting the data for troubleshooting of Mechanical Breakdowns
- Carrying out the necessary Maintenance activities and ensuring production lines are running effectively
- Communicating the Vision system, hardware networking onto the PLC by establishing an Ethernet connection
- Setting up the software, IP addressing to the machine to enable remote access operation

# Maintenance Engineer Intern, Pinewood Healthcare, Co. Waterford February - November 2021

- Performed PLC Programming and operating the HMI for the Machinery in Productions Lines
- Modified multiple machinery PLC code (Allen Bradley, Panasonic PLC's) using ladder logic for operability, readability, and troubleshooting
- Ensuring Preventive Maintenance, Corrective maintenance activities are carried out as per the Schedule.
- Installation and maintenance of plant equipment in several production lines.
- Keeping track of Maintenance KPI's and Designing detail-oriented Graphical reports of Production Lines using Advanced Microsoft Excel skills explaining the downtime, run time, MTTR, MTBF, speed and OEE
- Ensured barcodes/pharma codes/data matrix are properly read onto the cartons using Vision system (Cognex)
- Supporting FAT/SAT and collaborated in Installation (IQ, OQ) and commissioning of Plant equipment
- Calibration and precise temperature testing for manufacturing of different recipes and products
- Documenting the list of approved and planned maintenance work that needs to be executed using CMMS (Computerized Maintenance Management System)
- Carrying out the maintenance work as per CMMS by constantly updating work orders, PM procedures and Assets with the Service dates.
- Completing the maintenance documentation work in line with the maintenance SOP's

# Electrical and Maintenance Intern, Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited (BHEL), India 2018 - 2019

- Read and modeled Single line diagrams, PLC terminal, and Wiring diagrams using AutoCAD Software
- Collaborated in the Installation, and calibration testing of new Electrical/mechanical equipment
- Studied the working and operation of PLC, SCADA, DCS and gained competent skills
- Installation of PLC panels, Distribution termination, and Termination of electrical motors

# **EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS**

<ul> <li>PG Diploma (Level-9) in Electronics Engineering (1.1 Honours with 70.3% aggregate)</li> <li>Stream: Embedded and Wireless Systems</li> <li>National University of Ireland Maynooth, Ireland</li> </ul>	2019 - 2020
<ul> <li>Bachelors in Electrical and Electronics Engineering (1.1 Honours with 71.7% aggregate)</li> <li>PVP Siddhartha Institute of Technology, India</li> </ul>	2015 - 2019

#### **QUALIFICATIONS**

Full Irish Driving License

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

### Health and Safety awareness training - Tokyo Electron Europe Limited, Ireland

- Certified in Safe Pass, Manual Handling, Arc Flash, Chemical and Safety Awareness
- Trained and Certified in Maintenance, Installation and Calibration of Semiconductor test systems equipment

#### GMP Certification at Pinewood Healthcare, Co. Waterford, Ireland

- Exposure to working within cGMP Guidelines and completed Manual Handling Course
- Ensuring products free from Contamination (Certified in Health and Safety, and Chemical Safety Awareness)

## Certification in Lean Six Sigma at IT Sligo, Ireland - May 2020 to June 2020

- 5S Approach (DMAIC), Reviewed Key performance Indicators
- Utilised various techniques in Quality Management like Process Mapping, histograms, DOE, and 5 why analysis